

Ming-Yang Ho

kaminyou.com

ikaminyou@gmail.com

github.com/Kaminyou

linkedin.com/in/kaminyou

+886 952792255

Summary -

A data scientist at aetherAl with 4+ years of experience in 2D/3D computer vision, natural language processing, machine learning, and deep learning algorithms development. Besides, I am also adept at web programming, cyber security, and cryptography.

Skills -

- Programming related
 - Python
 - •C/C++
 - PyTorch
 - ReactJS
 - MySQL
 - Docker
 - Linux
 - •Git
- Domain
 - •2D/3D computer vision
 - Natural language processing
 - Cyber security
 - Computer security

Language -

- Mandarin (native)
- •English (TOEIC 825) [2014]
- ·Japanese (JEPT N1) [2021]

Work experience

Data Scientist

aetherAI, Oct. 2021 - (Current)

- Developed and improved algorithms for various 2D/3D computer vision tasks.
- •Invented Kernalize Instance Normalization and published to ECCV 2022 (1st author)
- •Supported backend and security teams.

Teaching Assistance (TA)

NTU EE Machine Learning, Feb. 2021 - Jul. 2021

NTU EE Web Programming, Feb. 2021 - Jun. 2021

NTU CSIE Bioinformatics and Cheminformatics, Sep. 2020 - Jan. 2021

Data Engineer Intern

Dcard, Jun. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- Developed new recommendation algorithms and maintained ETL tasks.
- •Invented and integrated an automatic image cropping system into our production.
- •Invented an efficient model to detect cyber warriors among 1,000,000+ users.

Software Engineer Intern

Institute of Information Science, Academa Sinica, Jul. 2019 - Aug. 2019

•Leveraged the concept of RGB channels to assist in SNP prediction.

Education

2019~2021 Master of Science (@NTU CSIE CMDM lab) GPA 4.2 (Best thesis award) Research topics: 3D computer vision, Machine learning, Computer security

Computer Science (bioinformatics specialization)

BEBI, EECS, National Taiwan University (NTU)

Look, Listen, and Diagnose: a deep learning based comprehensive Parkinson's disease evaluation system with 3D point cloud and acoustic features

2014~2019 Doctor of Pharmacy GPA 4.1 (CS-related GPA: 4.3, Outstanding Graduate Award) *Also got admitted to NTU CSIE in 2014.

Clinical Pharmacy

Pharmacy, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University (NCKU)

Honors

2021 PyCon APAC Speaker

Get 3D models out of nothing: Python implementation of deep learning-based 3D models reconstruction from 2D images..

2021 PyCon TW Speaker

Implementation of a deep learning-based saliency detection system by Python

2020 HITCON Speaker

Potential Security and Privacy Issues in Novel Taiwanese National eID system

Awards

2022 Best thesis award

2021 Multi-label Classification on CT Medical Imaging Competition, 3rd prize

2019 Outstanding Graduate Award

Recent Projects

2022 NTU wheel of dinner

Developed a dinner wheel for NTU students, which currently has 2,000+ users (https://github.com/Kaminyou/NTU-Dinner-Wheel)

2021 SUPERB: Speech processing Universal PERformance Benchmark Entrusted by NTU, CMU, MIT, and Facebook AI to build a leaderboard web server for SUPERB Benchmark. (https://superbbenchmark.org/)

Publications

*Ho, M. Y., et al. (2022) Ultra-high-resolution unpaired stain transformation via Kernelized Instance Normalization. ECCV 2022. (*first and corresponding author)

Ho, M. Y., Kuo, M. C., et al. (2022) Look, Listen, and Diagnose: a deep learning based comprehensive Parkinson's disease evaluation system with 3D point cloud and acoustic features. [under review]

*Liu, L. C., *Ho, M. Y., Su, B. H., Wang, S. Y., Hsu, M. T., & Tseng, Y. J. (2021). PanGPCR: predictions for multiple targets, repurposing and side effects. Bioinformatics, 37(8), 1184-1186. (*equal contribution) Ho, M. Y., et al. (2020) Potential security and privacy issues in novel Taiwanese National eID system.

TANET 2020 Ho, M. Y., Kuo, M. C., et al. (2022) A 2D camera is all you need: gait analysis with frontal-view 2D video

by deep learning-based 3D estimation. [unpublished manuscript]